(イバラ)ねぇ あの子。
Say, that boy...
He's the one. The only one
who failed to make it!
(ツバキ)例の子よ
１人だけ落ちたらしいわ。
Humph! Good for him!
(イバラ)いい気味よ
あんなのが忍になったら大変よ。
It would be terrible if someone
like him became a ninja.
I mean that boy is actually...
だってホントは あの子…。
(イバラ)ちょっと！
Don't say another word.
It's taboo.
それより先は禁句よ。
(ナルト)クソッ 何で
こんなことになってんだよ！
Damn! What's with all this?!
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
Heir to Darkness
(シラナミ)もしものために
念を入れておいたが➡
Good thing I took extra measures,
just in case.
正解だったな。
ヤツらは まだ戻ってきていないか。
They haven't returned yet.
(サクラ)ナルト！
テメエ！
Naruto?
Why you...!
(ヤマト)待て ナルト！ やめるんだ!!
Wait, Naruto! Stop!
いいや ヤマト隊長！
No, Captain Yamato!
Let me just say this!
これだけは
絶対 言わせてもらうってばよ！
遁兵衛のジイちゃん アンタ➡
Old man Tonbei!
You knew the Forbidden Jutsu
was embedded
禁術がホタルの体に埋め込まれてた
ってことを知ってたんだろ！
into Hotaru's back, didn't you?!
どうなんだよ！
Answer me!
禁術が あの小娘に？
The Forbidden Jutsu is in that girl?
(遁兵衛)木ノ葉の方がた。
Friends of the Hidden Leaf...
(ホタル)やめてください！
あれは お爺様が…。
Please stop!
It was my grandfather.
アンタ ずっとホタルのジイちゃんの
側にいたんだろう。
You served Hotaru's grandfather
all through the years, didn't you?
だったら 何で止めなかったんだ！
So why didn't you stop him?!
やめてください ナルトさん。
いいや！ やめねえ!!
Please stop, Naruto-san!
No, I won't stop!
そのせいで そのせいでお前は…。
Because of that...
Because of that, you're...
(ホタル)私が頼んだんです！
I asked that it be done!
な なんだって!?
What did you say?
私が 私が禁術をと頼んだのです。
I... I asked for the Forbidden Jutsu!
ホタル様…。
Hotaru-sama...
(ウタカタ)
ホタル どうしてそんなことを…。
Hotaru... Why do such a thing?
遁兵衛 無事でよかった。
Tonbei... I'm glad you're all right.
それは私のセリフです ホタル様。
I should say that about you,
Hotaru-sama.
木ノ葉の方がた ウタカタ殿。
Friends of the Hidden Leaf...
Utakata-dono...
何から何まで世話になり
かたじけない。
I am beholden to you
for all you have done for us.
(ヤマト)いえ ですが
土蜘蛛の里には➡
Don't mention it.
But the Tsuchigumo Village was already
under the bandit's control.
すでに盗賊たちの手が…。
そうですか それでここに。
はい。
I see... And that is why
you returned here...
Yes.
そんなことより さっきの話の
続きを聞かしてくれ！
Never mind that.
Tell us the rest of what
you were saying earlier!
(遁兵衛)禁術ことでしたね。
あぁ。
About the Forbidden Jutsu?
Yeah.
それが
お爺様の夢だったからです。
It was Grandfather's dream.
役行者の…。
En no Gyoja's...?
(ホタル)かつての土蜘蛛一族は
強力な禁術を持つことで➡
The Tsuchigumo Clan was once
hailed as a proud clan.
By possessing
a powerful Forbidden Jutsu,
大戦の戦況を
左右するとまで言われた➡
we were said to even be able to tilt
the balance of the Great Ninja War.
誇り高き一族でした。
けれど 禁術のために
土蜘蛛一族は➡
But at the same time,
our clan was targeted often
because of the Forbidden Jutsu.
常に命を狙われ １人また１人と
命を落としていった。
And one life after another was lost.
大戦が終わったとき➡
When the Great War was over,
禁術の使い手で生き残ったのは
ごくわずかでした。
only a few remained who could
wield the Forbidden Jutsu.
しかも 役行者様と里長との間で
一族の存続について意見の衝突。
Furthermore, En no Gyoja-sama and
the village elder had disagreements
over the clan's survival.
そのため 土蜘蛛の里と
ここ葛城山とに➡
This led to the clan splitting
into two groups
with one in
the Tsuchigumo Village and
一族は 分かれることに
なってしまったのです。
the other at Mount Katsuragi.
しかも 役行者様は
かなりのご高齢。
However, En no Gyoja-sama was
already quite advanced in years
葛城山に集う者は
ほどんどおりませんでした。
and few opted to follow him
to Mount Katsuragi.
((役行者 : ホタル 頼んだぞ。
Hotaru... I'm counting on you.
土蜘蛛一族の未来を。
The future of the Tsuchigumo Clan...
(お爺様!!))
Grandfather!
お爺様は 土蜘蛛一族の
名を守ることこそが➡
Grandfather believed that
protecting the Tsuchigumo name
禁術のために
命を落とした者たちへの➡
was the way to make amends and
せめてもの罪滅ぼしだと
信じていました。
honor those who lost their lives
for the Forbidden Jutsu.
だから 私は師匠である
お爺様の思いを継いだのです。
That is why I want to carry
on the wish of my grandfather,
who was my master.
バカだよ。
How stupid.
そんなことで
禁術を自分の体に…。
Just for that you had the Forbidden Jutsu
embedded in your body?
師匠だの一族だの
バカげてる。
For your master, for your clan...
It's all so stupid.
たとえ そうでも
師匠の遺志を継ぐのは➡
Even so, it's a student's duty
to carry out
弟子の務めです！
the wishes of her master!
ホタル…。
Hotaru...
わかりません。
ウタカタ様に私の気持は。
You wouldn't understand...
Master Utakata... how I feel.
ホタル様。 ウタカタ殿の
言うとおりかもしれませぬ。
Hotaru-sama,
perhaps Utakata-dono is right.
遁兵衛…。
Tonbei?
もはや 土蜘蛛一族に禁術を
守り抜く力がないことは明白。
It is evident that
the Tsuchigumo Clan no longer
has the strength
to safeguard the Forbidden Jutsu.
禁術を悪用されれば
役行者様も➡
If we allowed the misuse
of the Forbidden Jutsu,
En no Gyoja-sama would
surely turn in his grave.
草葉の陰で泣くに泣けぬ。
悪用を避けるには もはや➡
To prevent its misuse,
禁術を葬る以外に
方法はありませぬ。
we have no choice
but to destroy the jutsu.
葬る!?
Destroy?
葬るってどうするんだよ？
And how would you do that?!
だって 禁術ってば
ホタルの体に入ってるんだろ？
The Forbidden Jutsu is
inside Hotaru's body!
まさか！
勘違いなさるな。
You don't mean...!
Don't get me wrong.
(サクラ)遁兵衛さん ムリしないで。
(遁兵衛)心配は無用です。
Mr Tonbei...
You mustn't move too much.
Do not be concerned.
何だこれ？
(遁兵衛)その巻物は➡
What is this?
En no Gyoja-sama entrusted me
with that scroll.
役行者様から
お預かりしたもの。
そのなかに ホタル様の体から➡
It contains the way to
remove the Forbidden Jutsu
禁術を取り出す方法が
記されています。
from Hotaru-sama's body.
え!?
そんな方法が あるんですか？
Is there such a method?
役行者様は
何の解除の方法もなく➡
En no Gyoja-sama would never have
embedded the Forbidden Jutsu
ホタル様の体に
禁術を施したりはしませぬ。
into Hotaru-sama without
a way to remove it.
そのようなことをする師が
どこにいましょうか。
What kind of master would
even think of such a thing?
許してください。
もっと早く進言すべきでした。
Please forgive me.
I should have advised you sooner.
禁術は ホタル様から抜き出せば
永遠に力を失ってしまう。
Once it is removed from your body,
the Forbidden Jutsu will
no longer have any power.
私も 一族再興に
未練があった。
I also longed to restore
the clan's former glory.
禁術が消えれば
その望みも消える。
Without the Forbidden Jutsu,
that dream would fade.
しかし これでよいのです。
そんな！
But this is how it should be.
You can't be serious!
どうか 木ノ葉の方々。
Friends of the Hidden Leaf...
ホタル様から
禁術を抜き取る手助けを。
Please help me remove
the Forbidden Jutsu from Hotaru-sama.
しかし そうなると
我々の独断で動くことは…。
However, we cannot make
such decisions on our own.
なら さっさと綱手のばあちゃんの
許可を取ろうぜ。
Then hurry up and get
Granny Tsunade's permission.
このままホタルを
放ってはおけねえ。
We can't just leave Hotaru like this!
待ってください！
私はまだ➡
Please wait!
I haven't decided to let go
of the Forbidden Jutsu yet!
禁術を手放すとは
決めていません！
しかし ホタル様…➡
But Hotaru-sama...
このままでは 禁術ばかりでなく
ホタル様の命までも…。
Not only the Forbidden Jutsu,
but also your life would be in peril!
私の命なんて!!
It's my life!
いいかげんにしろ！
Come to your senses!
ウタカタ様…。
Utakata-sama...
す… すまない。
I-I'm sorry.
ウタカタ様は➡
Are you telling me to abandon
my clan pride and honor?!
私に 一族の誇りを
捨てろというのですか!?
おい 待て！
ナルト！
Hey, wait!
Naruto!
オレが 連れ戻す！
I'll bring her back!
ホタル様…。
Hotaru-sama...
オレが 説得してくる。
I'll go and convince her.
待ってください！
あなたに動かれたのでは…。
Hold on, please!
We cannot let you move around.
遠くへは行っていまい。 すぐ戻る。
She can't have gone far.
I'll be right back.
ホタルを 危険にさらしたりしない。
I won't put Hotaru in danger.
わかりました。
All right. Sakura, go with him!
サクラ！ ついていくんだ。
はい！
Yes, sir.
探索なら ボクのほうが適任では？
I'd be better at scouting her out.
キミには 今から
やってもらいたいことがある。
There's something I want you
to do right now.
はい。
Yes, sir.
お爺様…。
Grandfather...
((ホタル… 見るがよい。
Hotaru... take a look.
かつて 土蜘蛛一族は➡
Once, the Tsuchigumo clan was
known far beyond those mountains,
あの 尾根の向こうまで
その名が轟き➡
ここに見える景色は
すべて 領地としていたのだ。
and all one could see from here
was part of our lands.
すごかったんだね ホタルの一族は！
Our clan was so grand, wasn't it?
泣いてるの？ お爺様…。
Are you crying? Grandfather...
ワシは 間違っていたのだろうか…。
Was I wrong?
(ワシが長でなければ
土蜘蛛一族は…))
If I had not been the leader,
would the Tsuchigumo Clan...?
へぇ～！ こんな所に
ジイちゃんの墓があったのか。
So your grandfather's grave is here?
そこで 摘んできたんだ。
I picked those near by.
ありがとう ナルトさん。
Thank you, Naruto.
こんだけ眺めがよければ
ジイちゃんも喜んでんな！
With a view like this,
your grandpa must be very happy
to be buried here.
きっと
お前のことを心配してるぞ。
I'm sure he's worried about you.
そのとおりだ。 帰ろう ホタル。
He's right. Let's go back, Hotaru.
ウタカタ様…。
Utakata-sama.
何をしている？ 行くぞ。
Well? Let's go.
けれど 私は…。
But I...
お前が本当に
一族の再興を願うなら➡
If you truly wish to restore
your clan's glory,
そんなものに頼る必要はない。
you don't need to rely
on such a thing.
人は 持て余す力を持てば
そこには 苦しみしか生まれない。
Having too much power only
gives rise to suffering.
《オレのように…》
I'm the prime example...
なぁ ナルト！
Right, Naruto?
えっ？
Huh?
まだ１つだけ 方法があります。
方法？
There's still one other way.
Another way?
土蜘蛛一族のなかには➡
There is someone named Shiranami
among the Tsuchigumo Clan...
シラナミなる者がいて➡
その者なら
この禁術を扱えるとか…。
who is able to use
the Forbidden Jutsu.
シラナミって？
Who's Shiranami?
お爺様の弟子です。
He is grandfather's student.
役行者の弟子？
En no Gyoja's student?
正確に言うなら
また弟子ということになります。
Well, more correctly,
he is the student's student.
シラナミ様の父上 ウネリ様は➡
Shiranami-sama's father, Uneri-sama,
was my grandfather's first student.
かつての お爺様の
一番弟子でした。
とても誠実で➡
I have heard that he was brilliant
with exceptional ninjutsu skills.
天才的な忍術の才能を
もった方だったそうです。
そして その息子のシラナミ様は➡
And it was said that his son,
Shiranami-sama, was even more skilled.
さらに その上の才能を
持っているといわれていました。
ですが 大戦のあと
シラナミ様の父上は➡
But during the Great War,
Shiranami-sama's father was killed
禁術を守るために 殺されました。
trying to protect the Forbidden Jutsu.
お爺様は まだ若かった
シラナミ様の身を案じて➡
Grandfather sensed that
Shiranami-sama was also in danger
里から逃がしたそうです。
and had him flee the village.
お爺様は
よく言っていました。
Grandfather often said that
if those two were here now,
あの親子が
まだ この里にいたら➡
今の状況は
変わっていたかもしれないと…。
this village would not be
in such dire straits.
けど そのシラナミってヤツは
どこにいるんだ？
So where is this Shiranami fellow now?
なんか知らないのか？
それは…。
You know of anything?
Well...
盗賊たちは いつ再び
襲ってくるかわからない。
There's no telling when
the bandits will return.
シラナミを捜す時間はない。
決めるんだ。 ホタル。
We have no time to look for Shiranami.
Make up your mind, Hotaru.
わかった！ そのシラナミってヤツ
オレが捜してきてやる。
All right then! I'll go and
find this Shiranami!
え？
勝手に何言ってんのよ！
What are you talking about?!
実はさ ホタル。
Actually... Hotaru...
オレにも お前と似たような
悩みがあるんだ。
I'm sorta in the same dilemma as you.
ナルトさんにも？
You too, Naruto-san?
ナルト！ それは…。
Naruto... that's...
詳しくは話せねえけど➡
I can't go into detail,
but deep down,
オレは それを心のどこかで
面倒なことだと思っていた。
I've always been troubled by it.
でも 今 こうしていられるのは➡
Anyway, I can be like this now
because people like Sakura-chan,
サクラちゃんや エロ仙人や➡
the Pervy Sage and all the rest
of my friends have stayed by me.
多くの仲間が
いてくれたおかげなんだ。
けど ホタル… お前は強えぇ。
But Hotaru, you're awfully strong.
面倒を自分から受け入れて
ずっと１人で苦しんできた。
You accepted those troubles
and you've suffered all alone.
一族を… そして
ジイちゃんの夢を背負って。
Carrying your clan and
your grandpa's dream on your shoulders.
だから オレは…
お前の望みを叶えてやりてえ。
That's why I want you to
fulfill your dream.
そのシラナミってヤツを見つければ
お前の仲間になるんだろ？
If this Shiranami fellow is found,
he'll be an ally, right?
そうなりゃ お前は１人じゃねえ。
Then you won't be alone.
もう
１人で苦しむ必要はねえんだ。
And you don't have to suffer
by yourself.
ナルトさん。
Naruto-san...
まぁ 心配すんな！
Now don't worry.
ここは このオレ
うずまきナルトが何とかしてやる！
Just leave it to me, Naruto Uzumaki.
１日…
いや ２日だけ オレに時間をくれ。
Give me one... no, two days.
必ず
シラナミを見つけてくるってばよ！
I'll find Shiranami without fail.
《これは驚いた。
What a surprise.
まさか こんなところで
オレの名前が出てくるとはな》
I never would've guessed my name
would be mentioned here.
(シズネ)何かトラブルでしょうか？
Is there some kind of trouble?
(綱手)なるほど。
だいたいは
想像していたとおりだな。
I see...
It's pretty much what I imagined.
どうなさいますか？
このまま 禁術を残し続けるのは
危険だろう。
What will you do?
It will be dangerous to keep
the Forbidden Jutsu intact.
ですが これには
禁術を残したまま➡
But it says here they want to
keep the Forbidden Jutsu
この娘を 里で保護したいと
書かれていますが…。
確かに… あの禁術を
第三者の手から➡
and guard the girl at the Leaf village.
Without a doubt, it's necessary
to keep the Forbidden Jutsu
守りきる必要があるな。
from falling into
a third party's possession.
しっかし 捜してやるって
大見得切ったはいいが➡
Cripes... I acted like finding the guy
was no big deal for me,
どこ捜しゃいいんだ？
まっ 考えてても始まんねえ！
ここは 人海戦術といくか！
but where do I start looking?
Well, it's no use thinking about it.
This calls for the strength
in numbers approach!
多重影分身の術！
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
《ナルトが？》
確かに シラナミが里に戻れば。
Naruto is...?
Indeed, if Shiranami returns
to the village, we could...
たった２日で
見つかるでしょうか？
Can he find him in only two days?
場合によっては それまで
待てないかもしれない。
We may not be able to wait
that long.
ナルトの帰りまでに
また盗賊の襲撃があれば…。
If the bandits attack again
before Naruto returns...
確かに… 我々は
いざというときのために➡
You're right...
禁術を解除する準備に
取りかかっておきます。
Just in case, we'll make preparations
and stand by to purge
the Forbidden Jutsu.
いいな？ ホタル。
はい…。
You understand, Hotaru?
どうやら 乖離の術には
薬品も使用するようだ。
Yes.
It looks like the Diremption Jutsu
requires potions.
サクラ。 薬品の調合を含め
準備は キミが指揮をとるんだ。
Sakura, you'll be in charge.
わかりました。
Mix the potion and be ready.
Understood.
((役行者様は
何の解除の方法もなく➡
En no Gyoja-sama would never
have embedded the Forbidden Jutsu
ホタル様の体に
禁術を施したりはしませぬ。
into Hotaru-sama without
a way to remove it.
そのようなことをする師が
どこにいましょうか。
What kind of master would
even think of such a thing?
うっ… し 師匠！
M-Master...?!
(ツルギ)違う ウタカタ！ ヤツは ハルサメは➡
No, Utakata! He didn't...
(お前を
殺そうとしたわけじゃない))
Harusame didn't try to kill you.
It wasn't like that.
《まさか…
ツルギの言ったことは本当なのか…。
Could it be...
that Tsurugi spoke the truth?
もしそうなら 師匠は
オレに何を伝えたかったんだ。
If so, then what was
Master trying to tell me?
ツルギと
もう一度 話をしなくては…》
I must speak to Tsurugi once more.
悪いけど
シラナミってヤツを知らねえかな？
Say, ever heard of a guy
named Shiranami?
シラナミって人 聞いたことないか？
Do you know a guy
named Shiranami?
そっか… 知らねえか。
I see... Don't know him, huh?
何でもいいんだ。
Anything you know?
わかったら 木ノ葉の
ナルトに教えてくれってばよ！
If you find out, tell me,
Naruto of the Hidden Leaf!
もう ダメだ…。
チャクラを使い果たしたのに
手がかりも 何もねえ…。
It's no use...
I've used up my chakra and
I don't even have a clue.
どうなすったね。
こんな道の真ん中で…。
What's the matter?
それが… 人捜してんだけど
見つかんなくって。
Standing in the middle
of the road like this.
Well... I'm looking for someone
ほう… なんて人だね？
and just can't seem to find him.
Hmm... Who might that be?
シラナミって人なんだけどさ。
A guy named Shiranami.
シラナミ… あぁ おるね。
Shiranami...
ウソ！ ホントか!?
ホントなのか ジイちゃん！
Oh, there is such a man.
No kidding!
Is that true?!
Are you sure about this, old man?!
あぁ… そうだ たしか
この山の向こうの滝の小屋で➡
Yes. There's a man by that name
who lives in a small hut
忍術修業をしてる方が
そんな名前だったんじゃが…。
by the waterfall beyond this mountain,
and does ninja training.
この山の向こうだな！
ありがとよ ジイちゃん！
Beyond this mountain, right?!
Thanks, old man!
見つけたぜ！
Found him!
ウタカタ様… まさか
もう行ってしまわれたのでは…。
Utakata-sama...
Don't tell me he already left...
《さぁ 出てこい ツルギ。
オレに もう一度
あの話を聞かせてくれ》
Come on out, Tsurugi.
Tell me what you had to
say one more time.
ウタカタが動き出しました。
Utakata is on the move.
そうか… ウタカタめ。
オレを誘ってるのか…。
I see... Utakata...
Is he trying to lure me?
行くぞ！
はっ！
- Let's go!
- Yes, sir!
What?!
here are the answers of the path
koko ni aru no wa kimi ga ima made erande michi no
you chose up till now, look and go on by yourself
kotae tachi yo hora jishin motte susumeba ii
it's very natural, like a rainbow over
totemo shizen na no amaeagari no
asphalt after a rainfall
asufaruto ni niji ga kakaru you ni
a lonely wind blew and
lonely kaze ga fuite
a feeling dawned on me
feeling ki ga tsuita yo
there are any answers anywhere
kotae wo doko ni mo nai kedo
call me, I got it already
call me wakatteru wa
with you, we'll always
with you ai wa itsu mo
love each other
atae au mono
for you
I'm sure one day you will
kitto kimi wa itsu no hi ka
be able to fly in the sky
kono sora wo toberu hazu dakara
no matter how many times we've stumbled for you
nando tsumaizuta to shite mo for you
there's only one thing important
taisetsu na koto wa hitotsu
which is to dream
yumemiru koto
so at least keep your heart open
kokoro dake wa tozasanaide ite
Next Episode
(ミッシェル)駄目よ 姉さん！ 離して!!
I finally got a lead!
(ルーシィ)絶対に離さない！
This Shiranami of
the Tsuchigumo Clan
あ… ああ～!!
(ミッシェル)ああ～っ!!
was supposed to be a skilled ninja...
I'm sure the guy training
in the mountains
must be the one Hotaru
is looking for!
Looks like I'll make it within
the time I promised.
Just sit tight, Hotaru.
I'll bring him to you right away!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Separation"
Separation
I've been looking for you, Shiranami-san!